{
  "questionnaires": [
    {
      "question": "What is the relationship between operating systems and computer hardware?",
      "answers": [
        "Operating system helps to make computer hardware available to the application programs. Without Operating System we cannot access computer hardware.",
        "Operating system dont helps to make computer hardware available to the application programs. Without Operating System we cannot access computer hardware.",
        "Without an operating system computer hardware is only an inactive electronic machine, which is inconvenient to user for execution of programs.",
        "Thus without operating system execution of user program or to solve user problems is extremely difficult."
      ],
      "correct_answer": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "How Buffering can improve the performance of a Computer system?",
      "answers": [
        "Operating system helps to make computer hardware available to the application programs. Without Operating System we cannot access computer hardware.",
        "A process refers to a program under execution. This program may be an application or system program.",
        "If C.P.U and I/O devices are nearly same at speed, the buffering helps in making the C.P.U and the I/O devices work at full speed in such a way that C.P.U and the I/O devices never sit idle at any moment."
      ],
      "correct_answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the primary differences between Network Operating System and Distributed Operating System?",
      "answers": [
        "Thus buffering proves useful for those jobs that have a balance between computational work and I/O operations. In other cases, buffering scheme may not work well.",
        "Network and Distributed Operating systems have a common hardware base, but the difference lies in software."
      ],
      "correct_answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "Explain the following allocation algorithms: First Fit",
      "answers": [
        "In the first fit approach is to allocate the first free partition or hole large enough which can accommodate the process. It finishes after finding the first suitable free partition.",
        "The first fit deals with allocating the smallest free partition which meets the requirement of the requesting process. This algorithm first searches the entire list of free partitions and considers the smallest hole that is adequate. It then tries to find a hole which is close to actual process size needed.",
        "It begins as first fit to find a free partition. When called next time it starts searching from where it left off, not from the beginning."
      ],
      "correct_answer": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "Explain the following allocation algorithms: Buddy's system",
      "answers": [
        "In the Buddy's system approach is to allocate the first free partition or hole large enough which can accommodate the process. It finishes after finding the first suitable free partition.",
        "In Buddy's system approach is to locate largest available free portion so that the portion left will be big enough to be useful. It is the reverse of best fit.",
        "The best fit deals with allocating the smallest free partition which meets the requirement of the requesting process.",
        "In buddy system, sizes of free blocks are in form of integral power of 2. E.g. 2, 4, 8, 16 etc. Up to the size of memory."
      ],
      "correct_answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "Explain the following allocation algorithms: Best fit",
      "answers": [
        "In the best fit approach is to allocate the first free partition or hole large enough which can accommodate the process. It finishes after finding the first suitable free partition.",
        "In best fit approach is to locate largest available free portion so that the portion left will be big enough to be useful. It is the reverse of best fit.",
        "The best fit deals with allocating the smallest free partition which meets the requirement of the requesting process. "
      ],
      "correct_answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the difference between Job and Process?",
      "answers": [
        "A process refers to a program under execution. This program may be an application or system program.\n\nJob means an application program and it is not a system program.",
        "A process refers to a program under execution. This program may be an application or system program.\n\nJob means an system program and it is not a application program.",
        "A job refers to a program under execution. This program may be an application or system program.\n\nJob means an application program and it is not a system program."
      ],
      "correct_answer": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "Increased CPU Utilization is:",
      "answers": [
        "Multiprogramming improves CPU utilization as it organizes a number of jobs where CPU always has one to execute.",
        "Turnaround time for short jobs is improved greatly in multiprogramming.",
        "In multiprogramming, more than one program resides in main memory. Thus memory is optimally utilized."
      ],
      "correct_answer": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "What are not the advantages of multiprogramming?",
      "answers": [
        "Increased CPU Utilization",
        "Increased Throughput",
        "Shorter Turn around Time",
        "Increased Throughput",
        "Improved Memory Utilization",
        "Increased Resources Utilization",
        "Increased Resources Utilization"
      ],
      "correct_answer": 6
    },
    {
      "question": "What is not a Highest Response Ratio Next (HRN) Scheduling?",
      "answers": [
        "HRN is non-preemptive scheduling algorithm.",
        "In Shortest Job First scheduling, priority is given to shortest job, which may sometimes indefinite blocking of longer job.t",
        "HRN is preemptive scheduling algorithm.",
        "For determining priority, not only the job's service time but the waiting time is also considered.",
        "In this algorithm, dynamic priorities are used instead of fixed priorities.",
        "So shorter jobs get preference over longer processes because service time appears in the denominator.",
        "Longer jobs that have been waiting for long period are also give favorable treatment because waiting time is considered in numerator."
      ],
      "correct_answer": 2
    }
  ]
}
